Nina Zhuxiaona Wei 魏祝晓娜

weizhuxiaona@gmail.com | 206.295.0500 | weizhuxiaona.github.io

SUMMARY

Multidisciplinary background in psychology, HCI, and design, 8 years in product and UX Design, 5 years building AI-powered products, diverse experience in design agencies, startups, and big companies, looking for my next design adventure in AI, mental health, fitness, and SaaS.

EDUCATION

Master of Human-Computer Interaction & Design University of Washington (UW), Seattle, WA B.S. of Applied Psychology Zhejiang Sci-Tech University (ZSTU), Hangzhou, China

WORK EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder, Head of Product & Design

2018 - present

Qokka Inc, Mountain View, CA

- Responsible for all things product and design, led a team of developers and designers building AI / NLP powered products;
- Helped raised ~ \$1M pre-seed funding, assisted in customer acquisition, business development, sales, and marketing.

Product Manager & Designer

2017 - 2018

DeepLearning.AI / AI Fund, Palo Alto, CA

- Led a team to incubate a chatbot to help people lose weight;
 - Provided advisory services to other projects such as Landing AI and Workera.

Designer & Researcher

2016 - 2017

Silicon Valley Artificial Intelligence Lab, Baidu Research, Sunnyvale, CA

- Solo designer, building AI-powered products from the ground up, launched TalkType Voice Keyboard, acquired 100K organic users in a few months, launched SwiftScribe transcribe software;
- Led the exploration and evaluation of a **Talking Toy** business idea;
- Led a research study on designing for conversational agents;
- Assisted in other **Speech / NLP** projects, such as multimodal smart speakers.

Designer & Researcher

2014 - 2016

Ilol.biz, PanoTagg, Quirky, Sourcebits, Matrix Partners, Whitespace, Junior.io

- Provide design and research services to various startups, agencies, and ventures.

CV Nina Zhuxiaona Wei

SELECTED SKILLS

Programming: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, Yaml

Product & Design: Product strategies, product management, project management, user research, data analysis, UX design, rapid prototyping, user testing, visual design

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Summer Research Assistant, Stanford University

2020

Pervasive Wellbeing Technology Lab, Supervisor: Dr. Paredes

- Advised Stanford students on software design, survey design, and pilot studies;
- Assisted in NIH grant proposals and manuscript preparations on AI-assisted mental health interventions.

Research Lead, Baidu Research

2017

Silicon Valley Artificial Intelligence Lab, Supervisor: Dr. Landay

- **Initiated a research project on speech-based conversational agents**, led a team of researchers on literature review, experimental design, participant recruiting to data analysis, manuscript preparations, and presentations;
- Authored a paper on IEEE Pervasive Computing.

PUBLICATIONS

- Wei, Z., & Landay, J. A. (2018). Evaluating Speech-Based Smart Devices Using New Usability Heuristics. *IEEE Pervasive Computing*, 17(2), 84-96. DOI: 10.1109/MPRV.2018.022511249
- **Wei, Z.** (2017). So You Want To Be An AI Designer?. *ACM interactions, 24*(4), 44-49. DOI: 10.1145/3106743
- **Wei, Z.** (2017). How can I help? A Look Into Mental Health Startups. *Healthcare in America*. Retrieved from
 - https://healthcareinamerica.us/how-can-i-help-a-look-into-mental-health-startups
- Wei, Z. (2017). This is the 25 Day Life of Lunabot. *Chatbots Life*. Retrieved from https://chatbotslife.com/this-is-the-25-day-life-of-lunabot
- **Wei, Z.** (2017). Voice, It's Just the Beginning. *Muzli Design Inspiration*. Retrieved from https://medium.muz.li/voice-its-just-the-beginning-9e40832073e3
- Zheng Y., **Wei, Z.**, Ge, L. (2013). College Students' Sex-Role Concept and Its Factors. *Chinese Journal of Applied Psychology*, 19(4).

PATENTS

- **Wei, Z.** (2018). Display Screen or Portion Thereof With Graphical User Interface. *USD812635S1*, *USD815110S1*, *USD817337S1*. U.S. Patent and Trademark Office.
- Wei, Z., et al. (2018). Systems and Methods for Improved User Interface. *US10481863B2*. U.S. Patent and Trademark Office.